[{"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339384", "question": "In the movie \"Stand By Me\", what cartoon character does Vern think can take Superman on?", "answer": "Mighty Mouse", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3d8", "question": "What moisturizer is derived from sheep's wool?", "answer": "Lanolin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c76b", "question": "The curlew is a type of what?", "answer": "Bird", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5990f901fa5fdd6dd25324f3", "question": "Who sang a cover of \"Never Can Say Goodbye\" in 1974?", "answer": "Gloria Gaynor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59a7f6096f5f79087132fb42", "question": "In finance, what does \"QRM\" stand for?", "answer": "Quantitative Risk Management", "category": "general"}, {"id": "592200e9a4edfd43a087add9", "question": "How many fielding positions are there in baseball?", "answer": "Nine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b310", "question": "Sun Yat-sen is considered the founding father of what country?", "answer": "Taiwan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6aa", "question": "What is the chemical symbol for the element Magnesium on the periodic table?", "answer": "Mg", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e7", "question": "What is the longest one syllable word in the English language?", "answer": "Screeched", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c955", "question": "In distance measuring, what does AU stand for?", "answer": "Astronomical Unit", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afae", "question": "What first ran from Paddington to Farringdon Street in 1863?", "answer": "The London Underground", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b93", "question": "Frank Sinatra died on the exact same night as the series finale of what popular TV show?", "answer": "Seinfeld", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a732", "question": "What river flows along the western border of Illinois?", "answer": "Mississippi River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59071d263745b36be73039d4", "question": "What Soviet operation forced over 2,000 scientists and engineers to relocate from East Germany to Russia to work on missile design and production?", "answer": "Operation Osoaviakhim", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339052", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Cry, the Beloved Country\"?", "answer": "Alan Paton", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339402", "question": "Which actor played the role of the Grinch in the 2000 movie \"How the Grinch Stole Christmas\"?", "answer": "Jim Carrey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a26d", "question": "McLean Stevenson played which character in the TV series \"M*A*S*H\"?", "answer": "Lt. Colonel Henry Blake", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60078c190eee65b76b9f266f", "question": "America stayed neutral in World War I until Germany threatened what?", "answer": "Commercial shipping (In March 1917, four U.S. commercial ships were sunk by Germany, and the U.S. declared war in April 1917.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396ca", "question": "The TV show \"Frasier\" ran for how many seasons?", "answer": "11", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febd8027e83c707845b2174", "question": "What was the name of the item Andy went to fetch from the storage room in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Hexlite", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdcf", "question": "Which two disciples of Jesus were called the \"Boanerges\"?", "answer": "James and John", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339265", "question": "What was Paul McCartney's Bond theme?", "answer": "Live and Let Die", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4de1406d333868d34d70e", "question": "Mustafa Kemal was the first President of which country?", "answer": "Turkey", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d98", "question": "What author created the character of Tom Joad?", "answer": "John Steinbeck", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a93b", "question": "What US state is home to the singer of Stephen Foster's \"Oh! Susanna\"?", "answer": "Alabama", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c552", "question": "To be classified as perennial, a plant must have a life cycle of more than how many years?", "answer": "Two", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aeab", "question": "Which Cuban President was overthrown by Fidel Castro in 1959?", "answer": "General Fulgencia Batista", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a60", "question": "In the Beatles song, who shot Rocky Racoon?", "answer": "Dan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b5a", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Tarzan of the Apes\"?", "answer": "Edgar Rice Burroughs", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ef7", "question": "Whose sensei is a rat named Master Splinter?", "answer": "The Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c6e", "question": "Who played the male lead role in the 1983 movie \"Staying Alive\"?", "answer": "John Travolta", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9ab", "question": "What would you suffer from with Hypotension?", "answer": "Low blood pressure\u00a0", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390de", "question": "What is the name of the leading female singer in an opera?", "answer": "Prima donna", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8a8", "question": "How many stripes are there on the US flag?", "answer": "13", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd9d", "question": "What color is the square that's the logo for H&R Block?", "answer": "Green", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59029f21cad1ec93f27df75c", "question": "At what popular Seattle market did Starbucks open its first store in 1971?", "answer": "Pike Place", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8b74601dd7bf43be5e7e2", "question": "What color were stop signs originally?", "answer": "Yellow", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a393", "question": "What country lies directly south of Detroit?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c246", "question": "What date did man first land on the moon?", "answer": "July 20, 1969", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59ae9431574a5ce6b56b8244", "question": "What job did Agatha Christie's second husband do?", "answer": "Archaeologist", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b01", "question": "Which character killed Lennie Small?", "answer": "George Milton", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339179", "question": "Who were the five members of sixties Rat Pack?", "answer": "Frank Sinatra, Sammy Davis Jr., Dean Martin, Peter Lawford, Joey Bishop", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c77cdd024f0f7a362efd543", "question": "Who was the captain of the Bonhomme Richard in the 18th Century??", "answer": "John Paul Jones", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59067ed5ff9c0647b50a807f", "question": "To what age did the US state of Hawaii change the legal smoking age on January 1, 2016?", "answer": "21", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3fd", "question": "Who succeeded James Garfield as US President?", "answer": "Chester A. Arthur", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6010c5df0775fa611bce67cd", "question": "The Chang Building in Bangkok, Thailand, was designed to look like what?", "answer": "Elephant -- AKA the Elephant Building, the skyscraper was intended to reflect the importance of elephants in Thai culture.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c69c", "question": "Syncope is the medical term for what?", "answer": "Fainting", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133babf", "question": "What company introduced the first canned ham in the US in 1926?", "answer": "Hormel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015e56efe83fe1f2a824bbe", "question": "In which country was Buddha born?", "answer": "Nepal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af0e", "question": "The Battle of Bunker Hill occurred during what war?", "answer": "American Revolution", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a635", "question": "The Silicon Valley is located in what California valley?", "answer": "Santa Clara Valley", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf1a", "question": "What is the colour of mourning in Turkey?", "answer": "Violet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8c0", "question": "What \"island\", the southern-most tip of Brooklyn, has three miles of famous boardwalk?", "answer": "Coney Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b50c", "question": "What chessman makes an L-shaped move?", "answer": "The knight", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c75", "question": "Whose look-alike archenemy was named KARR?", "answer": "KITT's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fbaed8f0738315b1fb74e31", "question": "What spell was used to trick the Goblet in \"Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire\"?", "answer": "Confundus Charm", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58b3708a1c3f17ccc40c8e15", "question": "Which floor of the Guinness Storehouse houses the Gravity Bar, where tourists can drink a pint of Guinness?", "answer": "Seventh floor", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389cb", "question": "What are the six characters in the title of Luigi Pirandello's play i search of?", "answer": "An author", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bba1", "question": "What is the name for the fingers of a fork?", "answer": "Tines", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c516", "question": "How many stars are in the Big Dipper constellation?", "answer": "Seven", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c75a", "question": "What is another name for the disease known as Varicella?", "answer": "Chickenpox", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ecaea45790ded87bb38fd8e", "question": "When measured from its underwater base, what is the tallest mountain?", "answer": "Mauna Kea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "601b4c8e49076251badbead7", "question": "What was the name of the space capsule that carried the first woman in space?", "answer": "Vostok 6 -- It carried Soviet cosmonaut Valentina Tereshkova in space on 1963.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca6b", "question": "Who was the second man to walk on the Moon?", "answer": "Buzz Aldrin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ad", "question": "Who recorded the international hit single \"Poker Face\" in 2008?", "answer": "Lady Gaga", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8f9", "question": "What US port is nicknamed the Brick City?", "answer": "Newark, New Jersey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fefc5086ce05a3942286f3a", "question": "What kind of gun does Harry Callahan use to kill Mick in the film \"Sudden Impact\"?", "answer": ".44 AMP Auto Mag Model 180", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b68c", "question": "What automaker produced a model named Stag from 1970 to 1977?", "answer": "Triumph", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c85", "question": "What is the name of the inflatable automatic pilot in the movie \"Airplane\"?", "answer": "Otto", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab98", "question": "What Australian state shares a nickname with the US state of Florida?", "answer": "Queensland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff0b565e662d71a53650ff9", "question": "What is Scout's real first name in \"To Kill a Mockingbird\"?", "answer": "Jean Louise", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1e9", "question": "Which US president lived in The Beeches?", "answer": "Calvin Coolidge", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffa3a8fc73aa70ea0b70adf", "question": "What is the oldest city in the world?", "answer": "Damascus (The capital of Syria has evidence of continuous habitation dating back at least 11,000 years)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff0b4f9e662d71a53650ff3", "question": "What did both of Edgar Allen Poe's parents do for a living?", "answer": "They were actors", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fec89acec223966ae8f8829", "question": "\"Fear takes flight\" is the tagline for what 2005 film?", "answer": "\"Red Eye\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef5b666ce05a3942286e15", "question": "Which actress was the first American to win a Ca\u00e9sar, the French equivalent Oscar, in 2015?", "answer": "Kristen Stewart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea3477ff048f679a45aaf8", "question": "What is the bone diseases that literally translates to \"porous bones\"?", "answer": "Osteoporosis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394a3", "question": "What was B.J.'s full name in the TV show \"B.J. and the Bear\"?", "answer": "Billie Joe McKay", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58d11a084fea7fe947a22293", "question": "What is the fear of politicians known as?", "answer": "Politicophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f3f", "question": "What's the highest-pitched instrument in the orchestra?", "answer": "The piccolo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff144a6b0ee8c595b6d39b6", "question": "What is the name of the first \"Sherlock Holmes\" novel?", "answer": "\"A Study in Scarlet\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a322", "question": "Which character did Bill Nighy play in the 2003 film \"Love Actually\"?", "answer": "Billy Mack", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b57185367df192a942e335d", "question": "The \"Strait of Magellan\" is part of which continent?", "answer": "South America", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "594d05821a1c922dd1ac64a3", "question": "What is Ronald Biggs famous for?", "answer": "Being one of the \"Great Train Robbers\"", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5990f8dafa5fdd6dd25324f2", "question": "Where did we meet Newkirk, Carter, LeBeau and Kinchlow?", "answer": "Hogan's Heroes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdc0ea1469bb8041d07a062", "question": "Which U.S. restaurant chain has the slogan \"Service with the speed of sound\"?", "answer": "Sonic", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133caf6", "question": "Which British physician developed the first effective vaccine against smallpox?", "answer": "Edward Jenner", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3c1", "question": "Which South American country shares its name with a nut?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad66", "question": "Shark Island was an infamous Civil War-era prison in what US state?", "answer": "Florida", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0e7", "question": "What was ALF's girlfriend from Melmac's name?", "answer": "Rhonda", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e9d", "question": "What painter used his trademark Benday dots in canvases like \"Drowning Girl\" and \"Whaam!\"?", "answer": "Roy Lichtenstein", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "597cd983e347d002c297e4cc", "question": "Which Oscar-winning actor's only film as a director was the 1961 western \"One-Eyed Jacks\"?", "answer": "Marlon Brando", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fa6", "question": "What animated trio is made up of Master Shake, Frylock, and Meatwad?", "answer": "Aqua Teen Hunger Force", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338954", "question": "What is the English title of the French novel \"Le tour du monde en quatre-vingts jours\"?", "answer": "Around the World in Eighty Days", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7cb9d877e98cb97778a1d", "question": "In what country would you find Mont-Saint-Michel?", "answer": "France", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b358b6d5db0d66a186cb557", "question": "Falcon State is located in which South American country?", "answer": "Venezuela", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5be582025415ba52ed6f0ac6", "question": "The town of Whitby in North Yorkshire is situated at the mouth of what river?", "answer": "River Esk", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c62f", "question": "Long-period comets are believed to come from where?", "answer": "The Oort Cloud", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ae8637d7f28483af1e7fdca", "question": "What country would you find Mount Elbrus in?", "answer": "Russia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c33b", "question": "How long does it take for light from the Sun to reach Earth?", "answer": "About 8 minutes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b987", "question": "In which year was the wearing of seat belts made compulsory in the UK?", "answer": "1983", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339af3", "question": "According to the lyrics of the Counting Crows song \"Mr. Jones\", what rock legend does the singer want to be?", "answer": "Bob Dylan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58d119944fea7fe947a2228f", "question": "What is tramp's nickname for the lady in \"Lady and the Tramp\"?", "answer": "Pidge", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a536", "question": "What mountain chain runs from Maine to Alabama?", "answer": "Appalachian Mountains", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a56b", "question": "In 1620, the Pilgrims established the Plymouth colony in which present-day US state?", "answer": "Massachusetts", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339244", "question": "What movie was hyped: \"Girls like me don't make invitations like this to just anyone\"?", "answer": "Pulp Fiction", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597ddf6d77980686f722d185", "question": "What city was host to the first official Association football game in 1863?", "answer": "London", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5909ce69bb53d1af658864f0", "question": "Who directed the 2003 film \"Elf\"?", "answer": "Jon Favreau", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ed6", "question": "According to Langston Hughes, what might \"dry up, like a raisin in the sun\"?", "answer": "A dream deferred", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be66", "question": "What phrase appears on the ribbon in the bald eagle's beak on a one-dollar bill?", "answer": "E Pluribus Unum", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58c8a4f090aac110e416706f", "question": "What fruit are Kriek lambics made with?", "answer": "Cherries", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff3c2694f032c0db195b481", "question": "How old was Catherine of Aragon when she was betrothed to Prince Arthur?", "answer": "Catherine was three years old", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bf1", "question": "In which city's harbor would you find the statue of The Little Mermaid?", "answer": "Copenhagen", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339889", "question": "What 1987 Michael Caine film has a zero rating on the website Rotten Tomatoes?", "answer": "Jaws 4 - The Revenge", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133988c", "question": "What Canadian television series did hip hop star Drake star as a main character?", "answer": "Degrassi: The Next Generation", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe735abeec85e375820b24f", "question": "Who said, \"If you have ten thousand regulations you destroy all respect for the law.\"?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c121", "question": "What kind of birds would you find in a gaggle?", "answer": "Geese", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bc9", "question": "The band Guns n' Roses was formed in what US state?", "answer": "California", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab1c27baab681b0929219f", "question": "What car did Chevrolet design the Camaro to compete with in 1966?", "answer": "The Ford Mustang", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b7ff8dd3a3a814d89068c4f", "question": "What is a group of clams called?", "answer": "A Bed", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bef6", "question": "Which Saint is said to have carried his own head for six miles after his death?", "answer": "Saint Denis", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58b371201c3f17ccc40c8e1d", "question": "Considered to be the oldest pub in the US, what year was the White Horse Tavern of Rhode Island opened in?", "answer": "1673", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad77", "question": "Who was the first person to fly solo across the Atlantic ocean?", "answer": "Charles Lindbergh", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9d7", "question": "What color is malachite?", "answer": "Green", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58e2f54e2e77afa695b03104", "question": "What is the capital of Maldives?", "answer": "Mal\u00e9", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9a3", "question": "What river was connected to Lake Erie by the Erie Canal?", "answer": "The Hudson River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133893e", "question": "What armless statue in the Louvre is described as \"the most famous work of art of the ancient Greek sculpture\"?", "answer": "Venus de Milo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5fe", "question": "What year was Jesus Christ (Jesus of Nazareth) born in?", "answer": "7 - 2 BC", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9e9", "question": "What is it that turns blue litmus paper red?", "answer": "Acid", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be52", "question": "Perfecto, torpedo, and parejo are all shapes of what?", "answer": "Cigars", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc35", "question": "What broadcasting company owns CNN?", "answer": "Time Warner", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acdc", "question": "What animal is said to have nurtured the founders of Rome, Romulus and Remus?", "answer": "Wolf", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd6a8236c0f9723ab15cb63", "question": "What is the best-selling beer in the U.S.?", "answer": "Bud Light", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5922038aa4edfd43a087ade3", "question": "What shapes are used in a Venn diagram?", "answer": "Circles", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c206", "question": "What year were the Olympic Games hosted in the US for the first time?", "answer": "1904", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391f2", "question": "What is the name of the cat in the Disney movie \"Cinderella\"?", "answer": "Lucifer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c616", "question": "What is the process called where a plant makes its food?", "answer": "Photosynthesis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b335", "question": "What brand of melty cheese was first introduced to the mass market in 1928?", "answer": "Velveeta", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c92a", "question": "What is a dromedary?", "answer": "One-humped camel", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd6a7486c0f9723ab15cb5d", "question": "What was the first toy advertised on television?", "answer": "Mr. Potato Head", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febb2d37e83c707845b2114", "question": "HIV stands for what?", "answer": "Human Immunodeficiency Virus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d28", "question": "What children's books character is friends with Christopher Robin?", "answer": "Winnie the Pooh", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339973", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what IQ does Comic Book Guy posses?", "answer": "170", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f99", "question": "What character from a pop song wears a face that she keeps in a jar by the door?", "answer": "Eleanor Rigby", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe69b9820565ad31a57c761", "question": "Jimmy Carter served in which military branch?", "answer": "U.S. Navy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58ab0c04baab681b09292167", "question": "What 2005 horror short film shares a name with a piece of jewelry?", "answer": "Rings", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339846", "question": "What TV family includes Gomez, Morticia, and Pugsley?", "answer": "Addams Family", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c91f", "question": "Which fish, previously thought to be extinct was rediscovered In 1939?", "answer": "The Coelacanth", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c5c", "question": "What Californian city was George Lucas born in?", "answer": "Modesto", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af23", "question": "In which battle was Horatio Nelson killed?", "answer": "Battle of Trafalgar", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339165", "question": "What is the model name and number of the spacecraft's computer in \"2001: A Space Odyssey\"?", "answer": "HAL 9000", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "596df9cdf0cc2631d16a3c65", "question": "In 1993, Billy Dean took his version of which 1977 pop hit by Dave Mason to #9 on the country charts?", "answer": "\"We Just Disagree\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd82445d0de9af39e9d46b9", "question": "Which U.S. president spoke English as a second language?", "answer": "Martin Van Buren", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba03", "question": "What type of race is the Preakness Stakes?", "answer": "Horse race", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339521", "question": "The line \"Heeere's Johnny!\" comes from which movie?", "answer": "The Shining", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe64146ae7e414034b5aeaa", "question": "Approximately how long did the gunfight at the O.K Corral in Tombstone, Arizona last?", "answer": "Thirty seconds", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b929", "question": "What card game has variations know as Cincinnati, Chicago and Lowball?", "answer": "Poker", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c734", "question": "Despite its name, what species of whale is most likely to die in mass strandings on the beach?", "answer": "Pilot whale", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c053", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Honduras?", "answer": "Scarlet macaw", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfed", "question": "Who was America's first billionaire?", "answer": "John D. Rockefeller", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a060", "question": "Who directed the 1982 movie \"The Thing\"?", "answer": "John Carpenter", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ab1b1ad4fda37788a9a1db3", "question": "Which author wrote \"The Regeneration\" trilogy?", "answer": "Pat Barker", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b358c355db0d66a186cb55c", "question": "Popular in the Balkans, what type of beverage is the \"Rakia\"?", "answer": "Fruit brandy", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca0c", "question": "What is the name of the largest moon of Jupiter?", "answer": "Ganymede", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a68", "question": "What TV family had a maid named Florence Johnston?", "answer": "The Jeffersons", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b82e", "question": "What does the abbreviation NASCAR stand for?", "answer": "National Association for Stock Car Auto Racing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a754", "question": "Which four US states begin with the word \"New\"?", "answer": "New Hampshire, New Jersey, New Mexico and New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca0e", "question": "Where in the body are the adenoids?", "answer": "Nasal cavity", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe6a48920565ad31a57c7be", "question": "What was the first live-stream video on the internet?", "answer": "A garage band performance", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af91", "question": "Who was assassinated by Leon Czolgosz?", "answer": "President William McKinley", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd62", "question": "What delicacy comes from Wagyu cattle?", "answer": "Kobe beef", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396e0", "question": "Where does SpongeBob SquarePants work?", "answer": "The Krusty Krab", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "592eb034f83302ff91e4649a", "question": "Which record label signed The Beatles in 1962?", "answer": "EMI", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ec1", "question": "What is the stage name of rapper Jayceon Taylor?", "answer": "The Game", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f45", "question": "What sheriff's alter ego was the masked \"El Kabong\"?", "answer": "Quick Draw McGraw's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecdd21ec223966ae8f88ff", "question": "Who introduced Johnny Depp to acting?", "answer": "Nicolas Cage", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a74", "question": "What was the name of the high school attended by Archie Andrews and his comic-book friends?", "answer": "Riverdale", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8b4be01dd7bf43be5e7c6", "question": "Why were bowler hats invented?", "answer": "To protect gamekeepers from low branches", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f04", "question": "What bird was used as an alias for CIA agent Joe Turner in a Robert Redford movie?", "answer": "The Condor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a820", "question": "What river forms much of the border between Washington and Oregon?", "answer": "Columbia River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339578", "question": "The movie, \"It's a Wonderful Life\", what did Clarence receive for accomplishing his task?", "answer": "Wings", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4d981508b8581f80b092ad", "question": "What iPhone models were announced and released in 2017?", "answer": "iPhone 8, 8+ and X", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fb08a71cf631c2414a13b60", "question": "What is singer Fergie\u2019s real name?", "answer": "Stacy Ann Ferguson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391b5", "question": "Which studio produced \"Bee Movie\"?", "answer": "DreamWorks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bac7", "question": "Which superhero\u2019s powers could be taken away by the color yellow?", "answer": "Green Lantern", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a44", "question": "What author created the characters Ponyboy and Sodapop?", "answer": "S.E. Hinton", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b272", "question": "What Filipino volcano's 1991 eruption produced ten times more ash than Mount Saint Helens had?", "answer": "Mount Pinatubo's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5da", "question": "What does M&M stand for?", "answer": "Mars & Murrie", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b358dd55db0d66a186cb564", "question": "Where would you most often come across a chicane?", "answer": "On a motor racing track", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fec8a51ec223966ae8f882f", "question": "Which famous music group were formerly known as the New Yardbirds?", "answer": "Led Zeppelin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5909cf4fbb53d1af658864f3", "question": "Which African country was released from British and French oversight on Christmas Eve, 1951?", "answer": "Libya", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a360", "question": "What city dug the first subway?", "answer": "London", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c227", "question": "Who claims to have invented the Mai Tai cocktail in 1944?", "answer": "Victor J. Bergeron", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6008df6cf4f3bc4a292f862a", "question": "What did Zacchaeus do in order to catch a glimpse at Jesus Christ?", "answer": "Zacchaeus climbed a tree so he could have clear view of the Messiah on his way to Jericho.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59f9bbd8364247bf200fb8a9", "question": "What country borders Zambia to the north?", "answer": "Congo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdf1", "question": "What rare economic condition results when rising prices and recession occur at once?", "answer": "Stagflation", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7c517877e98cb977789aa", "question": "What London landmark is protected by six ravens?", "answer": "Tower of London", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a898", "question": "What city is home to the Telstra Tower?", "answer": "Canberra", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59c1cf0c7bd84c0ea43ad43e", "question": "The song \"The Obvious Child\" was a hit in 1990 for which singer?", "answer": "Paul Simon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133914a", "question": "Who wrote the 1975 novel \"Shogun\"?", "answer": "James Clavell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4e2", "question": "What fruit comes in Redhaven and Harmony variety?", "answer": "Peaches", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b553", "question": "How many official jelly belly flavours are there?", "answer": "40", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396aa", "question": "What brand of beverage has its containers visible in many shots in the movie \"Fight Club\"?", "answer": "Starbucks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea421cff048f679a45ab74", "question": "How many faces are there in an icosahedron?", "answer": "Twenty", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b05", "question": "What year was Charles Darwin's work, \"On the Origin of Species\", published?", "answer": "1859", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5be57fff5415ba52ed6f0ab0", "question": "Which TV show was set in the fictional town of Dunn's River, Connecticut?", "answer": "Soap", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb40", "question": "What color is the 4-ball in a game of pool?", "answer": "Purple", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6a4c320565ad31a57c7c2", "question": "What US President appointed the first Black Supreme Court justice?", "answer": "Lyndon B Johnson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339eb6", "question": "What's the last name of Clint Eastwood's character \"Dirty\" Harry?", "answer": "Callahan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bd05b4540191c55fd523fb1", "question": "Which person is most often associated with SpaceX and Tesla?", "answer": "Elon Musk", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a4a98fa61d1b4d384d5d694", "question": "What year did the radio show \"Gunsmoke\" debut as a TV show?", "answer": "1955", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a49c", "question": "What is the deepest part of the Atlantic Ocean?", "answer": "Milwaukee Deep", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339041", "question": "Which is the only book published by Margaret Mitchell during her lifetime?", "answer": "Gone with the Wind", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1d4", "question": "The Grasshopper cocktail originated from which New Orleans bar?", "answer": "Tujague's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba6e", "question": "What was Princess Diana\u2019s maiden name?", "answer": "Spencer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4de8b06d333868d34d717", "question": "Which Roman Emperor built a massive wall across Northern Britain in 122 A.D.?", "answer": "Hadrian", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fde4b1cc6c6b019850c9a79", "question": "What is the name of the Palestinian uprising that began inside Gaza and the West Bank in 1987?", "answer": "First Intifada", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398ff", "question": "What \"Seinfeld\" co\u00ad-creator also provided the voice of George Steinbrenner on the show?", "answer": "Larry David", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b970", "question": "Which French beer is also Melton Mowbray area code without the initial 0?", "answer": "1664", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6014c52ffbde8045e48466a8", "question": "What characteristic is unique to cetacean creatures?", "answer": "A blowhole -- Cetaceans (whales, porpoises, and dolphins)  use the blowhole on top of their head to breath oxygen.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59071da73745b36be73039db", "question": "Who became the first American in space in 1961?", "answer": "Alan Shepard", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600787ce0eee65b76b9f265d", "question": "According to Greek mythology who was the first woman on earth?", "answer": "Pandora", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b537", "question": "How many dots are there on a pair of dice?", "answer": "Forty-two", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4ca", "question": "What is the capital of the state of Utah?", "answer": "Salt Lake City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58b8d4d22b42d4a3561a9efc", "question": "In the comic book series \"Strangers in Paradise\", which employee of Mrs. Parker was framed with stealing $850,000 from Senator Chalmers?", "answer": "Samantha", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015def4fe83fe1f2a824b75", "question": "What percent of Russian males born in 1923 survived World War II?", "answer": "20%", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c695", "question": "The scientific unit named for Sir Isaac Newton measures what?", "answer": "Force", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a47", "question": "For what 1995 movie did Kevin Spacey win a Best Supporting Actor Oscar?", "answer": "The Usual Suspects", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6007810cbd51d85e222ab647", "question": "What art movement literally means the style of \"the wild beasts\"?", "answer": "Fauvism\u00a0(The movement emphasized vivid expressionism and unnatural use of color over representational or realistic values.)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff6706e52a821ff76ae8b21", "question": "What is a cartomancer?", "answer": "A fortune teller who uses cards", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5901d8bd709c1c34536e6ea6", "question": "In what country was the first coin operated slot machine invented?", "answer": "US", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afb3", "question": "Which Egyptian city was founded by Alexander the Great in 331 BC?", "answer": "Alexandria", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1c5", "question": "What is the only sign in the zodiac which is not represented by a living thing?", "answer": "Libra", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ead", "question": "What screen legend made his final appearance in the movie \"The Score\"?", "answer": "Marlon Brando", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600241334be4723ccac22172", "question": "A painting by what artist was once mistakenly hung upside-down at MoMA?", "answer": "Henri Matisse -- A stock broker, familiar with Matisse's work, noticed \u201cLe Bateau\u201d was hanging upside down at the museum in NYC.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4aa", "question": "The star Polaris is more commonly known by what name?", "answer": "The North Star", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1b0", "question": "Who beat Martina Navratilova in the Wimbledon Women's Singles final in 1994?", "answer": "Conchita Martinez", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4bf", "question": "What is the only nation that borders both Mauritania and Guinea-Bissau?", "answer": "Senegal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c254", "question": "What is acetylsalicylic acid commonly known as?", "answer": "Aspirin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c61c", "question": "What is the chemical symbol for Helium?", "answer": "He", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae7d", "question": "Which US president ordered the first troops into Vietnam, starting the ground war for the US?", "answer": "Lyndon B. Johnson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389ae", "question": "What painter's mental state is revealed in 750 letters he wrote to his brother Theo?", "answer": "Vincent van Gogh's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b91a", "question": "The word alphabet comes from which 2 Greek letters?", "answer": "Alpha and Beta", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a022", "question": "In the TV show \"Family Guy\", who is Stewie's half-brother and nemesis?", "answer": "Bertram", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c163", "question": "What airport has the code MME?", "answer": "Durham Tees Valley", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff0b8f2e662d71a5365102a", "question": "The opener of \"Fahrenheit 451\" says it\u2019s a pleasure to what?", "answer": "Burn", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff141a8b0ee8c595b6d39a5", "question": "Who wrote \"James and the Giant Peach\"?", "answer": "Roald Dahl", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe76e2deec85e375820b2db", "question": "Where did bungee jumping originate?", "answer": "Vanuatu", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab1e", "question": "Which coast of Australia is Sydney located on?", "answer": "East", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd96e5b23c87fd04dd15e36", "question": "Which U.S. president owned a pet hyena?", "answer": "Theodore Roosevelt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339be0", "question": "What popular singer had a chimpanzee name Scatter?", "answer": "Elvis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5990f8a6fa5fdd6dd25324ef", "question": "Which city is home to Colman's mustard?", "answer": "Norwich", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ad7ebfdb24f84e0b9f9ffe2", "question": "The song \"Honolulu Baby\" was written for which Laurel and Hardy film?", "answer": "Sons of the Desert", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a009", "question": "What color are Chip 'n' Dale's noses?", "answer": "Black and red", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba21", "question": "What is the name given to the Cricketer's Year book, where all cricketing laws and scores are reported?", "answer": "Wisdens Almanac", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd87", "question": "What type of animal is the Japanese monster, Kumonga?", "answer": "Spider", "category": "general"}]